I had an interview today, too.
I had a great interview
with Admissions at Columbia University.
Really?
What did they say?
Will you get into the school?
Well, they didn't say anything for sure.
But I figure that with my grades and with my personality,
I'll have no problem.
Columbia's a terrific school.
What are you going to do?
Do? I don't know.
I also applied to NYU.
You sound excited about Columbia.
What's your problem, Mike?
Indecision. Indecision.
It's not easy,
and this is an important decision we have to make.
What about you?
How was your interview with Michigan?
The interview was fine.
It's a great college.
It is.
My father would like me to go there.
He and my Grandpa both went there.
Great medical school, too.
I know.
You can follow in your father's footsteps.
Ah! I'd like to follow in my own footsteps, Mike.
What do you want to study?
I've been thinking.
I think I want to study journalism
to be a reporter--a newspaperman.
You do a pretty good job on the Riverdale High School paper.
And I've been thinking about it a lot lately.
Have you discussed it with your parents?
No. But I have to.
OK. Let's talk.
Hi, Son. Is everything all right?
Hi, Dad. Everything's fine.
I was just waiting for you to get home
so we could talk.
Anything special you want to talk about?
There is, Dad.
I'm listening.
Well, I know you and Mom have given up a lot
to save money for my college tuition.
We want you to go to college, Robbie.
I know. I do.
But?
Well, I've thought a lot about which college,
and one of them is Columbia.
Columbia? Why Columbia?
First, they have an excellent School of Journalism.
They do.
And your friends are planning to go to Columbia?
That's only part of it.
It's complicated.
I'll try to explain.
Mike and I had a hamburger this afternoon, and we talked.
Yes?
Well, we talked about a lot of things.
He applied to Columbia,
and his interview was very successful.
He thinks he'll be accepted,
and he really wants to go there.
Dean Rafer called me today.
He told me he was very impressed with you.
He's a nice man.
He was very kind.
He told me
you had some doubts about wanting to go to Michigan.
Yes. I do.
I'm just not sure about what I want to do.
That's OK.
You understand?
Let me tell you something, Robbie.
Something that might be surprising to you.
What? Tell me.
Well, Grandpa wanted me to study engineering, like him.
Well, I wasn't clear about my future,
but I knew engineering was not for me.
What did you tell Grandpa?
The truth.
Then you're not upset
about my not wanting to go into medicine?
I'm not upset at all.
I'm just happy that we're able to talk about it.
I am too, Dad.
I suppose you want to apply to Columbia.
Yes, but I also want to apply to several other colleges.
I thought you wanted to go to Columbia.
Well, I might want to go to Columbia.
But I might not.
I just want to be able to make my own decision.
You're a real Stewart!
And if I think about it long enough, you never know ...
Never know what?
If I make my own decision,
I might choose Michigan.
Robbie, you're something!
You know, when I was your age,
I said exactly the same thing to Grandpa.